How much empathy do you feel towards other people?
你对他人有多少同情心哪？
If you saw someone fall off their bike in traffic, would you stop and help - or just walk away?
如果你看到有人在车流中从自行车上摔下来，你会停下来帮忙，还是直接走开？
Many people would give in to apathy, go about their business and just do nothing.
许多人会选择冷漠，忙于自己的事，什么也不做。
So it was a big surprise when about 100 bystanders got together recently to move a bus in east London to help a cyclist trapped under it.
因此，最近当大约100名旁观者聚集在伦敦东部，一起移动一辆公交车以帮助被困在车下的骑自行车的人的时候，这让人大吃一惊。
A video of the incident went viral on social media.
这一事件的视频在社交媒体上疯传。
According to Zoheb, a driver who stopped his car to take part in the rescue, about five people gathered to move the bus.
据参与救援的司机佐赫布（Zoheb）说，最初大约有五个人聚集在一起来移动公交车。
He says: "There was no chance we could do it, it was more an invitation for other people to help, really".
他说：“我们不可能做到，这更像是邀请其他人来提供帮助。”
The initiative paid off.
这一倡议取得了成功。
Diners from nearby restaurants joined in.
附近餐馆的食客加入了进来。
There wasn't much coordination but it didn't take long to develop a collective understanding of what the objective was.
虽然没有太多协调，但人们很快就全部理解了什么是行动目标。
Spontaneous collaboration among strangers doesn't happen often.
陌生人之间的自发合作并不常见。
People in a crowd are not sure what to do - they don't have a plan.
群体中的人们不确定该做什么——他们没有计划。
It's one of the reasons bystanders often do nothing, according to... Dr Mark Levine, professor of social psychology at Exeter University in Britain.
英国埃克塞特大学社会心理学教授马克·莱文（Mark Levine）博士表示，这是旁观者经常什么都不做的原因之一。
"The presence of others can inhibit you from helping", he says.
他说：“其他人的存在可能会阻碍你提供帮助。”
The key to positive group behaviour and intervention, Levine explains, "is building a sense of shared identity".
莱文解释说，积极的群体行为和干预的关键是“建立一种共同的身份认同感”。
Action has to be decided quickly, Levine says.
他同时还说，必须迅速决定行动。
"The longer you leave it, the harder it is to make a decision.
“拖得越久，做决定就越难。
If you don't immediately act then you kind of think 'Well, actually I probably couldn't have done anything anyway'."
如果你不立即采取行动，你可能就会想，‘嗯，其实我可能什么都做不了。’”
But the people who took the initiative like Zoheb might make a difference.
但像佐赫布这样主动采取行动的人可能会带来改变。
The cyclist ended up in hospital and the images of the collective effort might inspire others to more acts of solidarity.
骑自行车的人最终被送往医院，而集体努力的画面可能会激励其他人采取更多齐心协力的行动。